{"test_questions": [[{"question": "An odd number of cross overs in inverted region will result into formation of a dicentric chromatid and acentric chromatid at anaphase I incase of", "opta": "pericentric inversion", "optb": "paracentric inversion", "optc": "double inversion", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The percentage of individual with a given genotype, which exhibits the associated phenotype, is defined as", "opta": "penetrance", "optb": "expressivity", "optc": "inheritance percent", "optd": "environmental influence", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Diethyl stilbestrol (DES), a synthetic estrogen causes", "opta": "chromosome lagging", "optb": "disruption of mitotic spindle", "optc": "centriole elongation", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bar eye character of Drosophila is due to", "opta": "duplication in region of 16A of X chromosome", "optb": "deletion in region of 16A of X chromosome", "optc": "due to presence of additional X-chromosome", "optd": "due to a point mutation in eye-locus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transmission of a gene from male parent to female child to male grand child is known as", "opta": "holandric inheritance", "optb": "quantitative inheritance", "optc": "criss-cross inheritance", "optd": "maternal inheritance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The degree or extent to which a given genotype is expressed phenotypically in a particular individual is defined as", "opta": "penetrance", "optb": "expressivity", "optc": "inheritance strength", "optd": "environmental influence", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many chromosomes are there in Caernorhabditis elegans?", "opta": "3", "optb": "6", "optc": "9", "optd": "12", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two genes show 50% recombination", "opta": "they are on different chromosomes", "optb": "they are on same chromosome but far apart", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "they are closely located on the same chromosome", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following denotes a pair of contrasting characters?", "opta": "Alleles", "optb": "Phenotype", "optc": "Homozygous", "optd": "Genotype", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A map of chromosomes that utilizes cloned and sequenced DNA fragments rather than genetic markers is known as", "opta": "a physical map", "optb": "a genetic map", "optc": "a cloning map", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a dihybrid cross, the progeny of an Fl individual (hetero2ygous for both characters) will show a phenotypic ratio of", "opta": "1:1:1:1", "optb": "1:2:2:1", "optc": "9:3:3:1", "optd": "3:1:1:3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an organism, the chromosome number is maintained constant because of", "opta": "independent assortment", "optb": "crossing over", "optc": "DNA duplication", "optd": "synapsis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many chromosomes are there in the budding yeast (S. cerevisiae)?", "opta": "16", "optb": "17", "optc": "18", "optd": "20", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct when a character shows continuous variation assuming a normal distribution?", "opta": "It is governed by many genes with small cumulative effect", "optb": "It is not controlled genetically", "optc": "Many of the variation is due to fluctuation of climate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Raphanobrassica is a classical example of", "opta": "aneuploidy", "optb": "nullisomy", "optc": "allopolyploidy", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How does dosage compensation in Drosophila occur?", "opta": "Hypertranscription of male X chromosome", "optb": "Hypotranscription of female X chromosome", "optc": "X inactivation in females", "optd": "Chimerism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hairy wing character of Drosophila is due to", "opta": "duplication in region of chromosome", "optb": "deletion in region of chromosome", "optc": "due to presence of additional X-chromosome", "optd": "due to a point mutation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A diagram depicting chromosomes of haploid set of an organism ordered in a series of decreasing size is known as", "opta": "zymogram", "optb": "chromogram", "optc": "idiogram", "optd": "karyogram", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cross shaped (+) or a ring involving four chromosomes may be formed during metaphase I in case of", "opta": "translocation heterozygote", "optb": "deficiency", "optc": "haploid organism", "optd": "duplication", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Incase of inversion when the inverted segment of chromosome includes centromere, it is known as", "opta": "paracentric inversion", "optb": "double inversion", "optc": "inverted inversion", "optd": "pericentric inversion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Exchange of segments between non homologous chromosomes is best known as", "opta": "translation", "optb": "translocation", "optc": "recombination", "optd": "crossing over", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}